- So far we've seen how natural language processing
or NLP can be broken down into two main AI concepts.
There's natural language generation or NLG.
This is where the AI system outputs texts
in a way that sounds more human.
Then there's natural language understanding or NLU.
This is when an AI system can analyze human generated text
and understand the overall meaning.
There's also automated speech recognition or ASR.
This allows a person to speak normally
then the ASR system recognizes these sounds
and transcribes them into text.
So when you combine natural language processing
with automated speech recognition,
you end up with an AI system that can interact
in a way that feels conversational.
In fact,
it's these combined concepts
that people are most familiar with.
Some of the largest companies,
such as Apple, Microsoft, and Amazon,
are creating virtual assistants that combine NLP and ASR.
When you talk to Siri, Cortana, or Google Assistant,
you might view this as one technology.
But in reality,
it's like combination of all of these technologies.
They work together to create a seamless experience.
But when you're thinking about these concepts
in your business,
you should really think about them as separate AI systems.
That way you'll apply the most appropriate technology
without spending extra money on things you don't need.
So think of it this way.
Amazon has encouraged businesses
to use their virtual assistant Alexa
to help book conference rooms.
But most large companies don't call people
on the phone to book these rooms.
That means that they don't really need
automated speech recognition or ASR.
In fact,
you might recognize that natural language understanding
or NLU is the biggest challenge
when using an AI system to book a conference room.
If the system understands what a person is saying,
then it shouldn't be too difficult
to connect to a scheduling system.
And it doesn't seem to necessary to spend too much time
with natural language generation or NLG.
Most of the response will just be the system telling you
whether the conference room is available.
So in this case,
it might make sense to use a virtual agent.
This can simply be a chatbot or an agent
that responds to texts or email.
That way people in your organization can open up
a chatbot client and have a simple text conversation.
In this case,
you understood that NLU would be the biggest challenge.
So you put a lot more emphasis on these tools
than you would on automated speech recognition
or natural language generation.
When you're using these tools to build your own system,
you should think about it in the same way.
Will your system spend most of the time writing,
understanding, or listening.
That way you can build a system
that will be the most helpful for what you need.