- You can use machine learning algorithms
to find patterns in your data.
Then you label the data in a few different ways.
With supervised machine learning,
you create your own labels,
and then the machine classifies the data using these labels.
With unsupervised machine learning,
you let the machine create its own labels
and organize the data into clusters.
Microsoft, Amazon, and Google, along with others,
have created their own machine learning systems as services.
That way, you can simply
give these services access to your data,
and allow them to do the heavy processing.
You'll see a few of these later on.
But as you can imagine,
working with these machine learning algorithms
can get complicated.
It's also difficult to gather and maintain
all the data that you need
to help these systems make decisions.
So you might be thinking,
"Why would your organization want to
go through all this trouble?"
There's certainly value in labeling your data,
but how will your business benefit from this labeling?
For that, you have to remember
that your organizational data itself
doesn't have that much value.
But what does have value
are the insights that you gather from the data.
In fact, one of the most valuable insights
you can get from your data
is around helping your company to make better predictions.
So think of it this way.
You could take several steps
to better predict your customer's behavior.
You could send a representative from your company
to interview them.
You could gather information about their interests
and their friends' interests.
You could invite in all their friends and family,
and ask them questions in a large focus group.
After all that, you'd probably do a pretty good job
predicting your customer's behavior.
But taking these steps is very expensive and time-consuming.
In fact, if you did this for all your customers,
you'd probably go out of business.
On the other hand, what machine learning allows you to do
is to push down the cost of these predictions.
So you can still get the benefit of all these extra insights
without all the costs.
When prediction becomes incredibly cheap,
then the range of things
that your organization can accomplish
becomes much greater.
This might seem like a strange or abstract concept,
but many organizations are already benefiting
from better predictions.
A lot of websites are very good at making suggestions
about what you might want to purchase.
Streaming services like Netflix
are very good at recommending new shows.
This level of prediction used to be very costly,
but now machine learning is pushing down that cost.
So to get the most from machine learning,
think about how you can use prediction
to better serve your customers.
If you can better predict their behavior,
then you can do a much better job understanding their needs.