- Deep learning is one of the most interesting areas
in artificial intelligence.
But when you're looking at different tools,
it's easy to mix up deep learning tools
with machine learning.
You can usually use any deep learning tool
to also do standard machine learning.
Remember that the difference between deep learning
and machine learning
is a matter of how many hidden layers you have
in your artificial neural network.
So in a sense, deep learning is just
very deep machine learning.
With that being said,
there are still some tools that specialize
in creating deep learning artificial neural networks.
Some of these are software tools
that you can install on your own systems.
While many of them are also services that you can use
to upload and analyze your own data.
Let's bring out the computer one more time,
so we can look through some of these deep learning tools.
Let's start by looking
at some of the great deep learning platforms
that are available.
We'll start with one of the most popular,
which was created by the Google Brain Project in 2011.
TensorFlow is an open source end-to-end
machine learning platform
that you can use with most cloud-based services.
It works with all the services we saw earlier,
Amazon, IBM Watson, and Microsoft Azure.
TensorFlow is cross-platform,
so that means that it runs
on a lot of different architectures.
You can run it on servers, smartphones,
and it even works on GPUs, or graphics processing units.
It abstracts a lot of the hardware using something
called the TensorFlow Distributed Execution Engine.
And then on top of the front-ends,
you have a bunch of models you can use
to train and evaluate your data.
One of the most popular is Keras.
So you can see that there's a guide
on how to install TensorFlow
and how to migrate to the next version of TensorFlow,
which is currently TensorFlow 2.0.
If you look at some of the code
that's included here in TensorFlow,
you can see that it includes a library called Keras.
Now, if you go to Karas' website,
you can learn more about this open source project.
You can click getting started,
and you can see an introduction here,
and it lists out the guides and the API.
Keras is a library written in Python
that sits on top of TensorFlow.
It's a very popular way to work with training data
in TensorFlow.
Another framework which you might want to use
is the Microsoft Cognitive Toolkit, or CNTK.
This is also part of the open neural network,
which is ONNX, and it's another competing framework.
You can also use Keras as part of CNTK,
like Keras, it's a Python library,
and you can go to GitHub and see CNTK here.
You can also see how to install.
This has been released by Microsoft under the MIT license.
You can see here that you can install CNTK in Windows,
Unix, and other operating systems.
If you're using your deep learning artificial neural network
to identify objects, it might be worthwhile
to take a look at another framework called Caffe.
It was developed by Berkeley AI Research, or BAIR.
Again, you could view this on GitHub,
it's available under the very permissive BSD license.
The GitHub page will give you an idea of how to install it.
If you want to learn a little bit more about it,
you could click on this Caffe in a Day
and it takes you to this slide show presentation
that gives you a lot of really specific examples
on using this framework for vision
to do some deep learning image classification.
So let's just close that up.
If you're just starting out
using these deep learning frameworks,
then you might want to take a closer look at TensorFlow.
It's one of the most active and popular ways
to create these networks
on almost all popular cloud-based services.
You can also run it on your own server,
smartphones, and many other devices.
It abstracts away most of the technical challenges
you get into when building these networks.
And you have a lot of flexibility
to run it on top of your existing technology.