- We've seen how artificial neural networks can crunch
enormous amounts of data
and because it's a network,
it doesn't operate the same way as one system.
It's usually not one giant computer.
Instead, it's a series of nodes
that work together to process data.
These nodes break the data into chunks,
then they make decisions about the data
and pass the information along to nodes in the next layer.
In many ways, the neural network reacts
to the data it's processing,
so it's not like a typical computer program.
It doesn't try to map out all the possibilities
and then follow a preprogrammed route;
instead, it reacts to the data in real time.
So artificial neural networks are different
from how most organizations think about computing,
and it might be hard to imagine how this technology
could work in your organization.
Before you set up your own neural network,
you may want to consider some of the best ways
to use this technology.
The first thing to keep in mind is
that neural networks learn by making mistakes.
It processes the data and then optimizes itself
in real time.
That means in the beginning,
your network might only be right
a small percentage of the time
but as your network learns, it will improve.
More and more often, it'll be correct.
That's why when you look at the results
of artificial neural networks,
it's typically displayed as a probability of being correct.
So if you look at something like facial recognition,
you'll notice that the neural network
will say something like, "This has a 98.6% chance
"of being a certain person."
So if you can handle a lot of mistakes
at the beginning of the process,
you could use these networks
to process your organization's data,
just be sure to focus on the strengths of this technology.
Artificial neural networks are great
for seeing associations or regularities in complex patterns.
This is especially true when you have a lot of diverse data
with patterns that are hard to recognize.
It can do really well
when humans don't understand these relationships
or they might be very difficult to describe.
So imagine you work for a retail organization
that owns shopping malls.
You want to look at the video footage of these malls
and see if you can find patterns in how people shop.
In this case, you have a very complex pattern.
You might have thousands of people
moving in various directions.
It's a diverse data set because there are many people
doing many different things.
No human could watch all this footage
and come up with a pattern,
but an artificial neural network can process all this data
and make recommendations
about where to put different stores.
The network could look for patterns,
then it could create visuals
that show the heaviest traffic areas.
So if you're thinking about using this technology,
keep these strengths in mind.
Remember that the machine will learn
as it processes the data.
So if you let it make a few mistakes in the beginning,
you can gain some real valuable insights.