- There are many cases
where you'd need a very specialized decision-making system.
You'd certainly want a specialized system
to evaluate X-rays, but there are also many times
where you'd use a more general form of decision-making.
We've seen this happening with banks and credit cards.
You've probably seen those websites
that promise a 30-second decision for a loan or credit card.
These websites typically use a form
of automated decision-making.
They'll look at your credit score,
and if you meet a certain criteria, you'll get approved.
Newer machine learning algorithms allow you to do this
in a much more sophisticated way.
These automated decision-making systems aren't limited
to a simple credit score.
Instead, these newer systems can look
at your employment history, your job history,
and even your social media data.
Because they're looking through so much more data,
they can usually make a much more accurate decision.
And machine learning can make accurate predictions
at a much lower cost.
In the past, you'd have a loan agent
and a lengthy application process.
The whole point of this process was to try and predict
whether you'd have trouble paying back a loan.
So the cost of deciding whether
to give you a loan was relatively high.
Now these newer systems can make a much more accurate
and less costly decision in seconds.
And since these systems give more accurate results
at a lower cost, they're now being used
for many different types of decisions.
Some businesses are using automated decision-making systems
to decide whether or not they should hire a new employee.
Some universities use similar systems
to decide whether they should admit a student.
If you're thinking about using a system like this
with your organization, then start by considering your data.
The most common system is one that classifies people
into certain groups.
Remember that many
of these automated decision-making systems
use supervised machine learning.
So you might classify people as high-risk loan candidates.
Remember that with supervised machine learning,
you start out by creating a small training set
to show the system how you want to classify the data.
In this case, you'll show the system how to classify people
into different risk groups.
So if you work for a bank,
you'd create a training set of applications
for people who didn't repay their loans.
Those would be your high risk loan candidates.
If you want to create a system that hires people,
then you'd want to create a training set
of employment applications for your most successful hires.
Then you'd train the system to look for people
with similar qualities.
You'd feed the data into the system
so it can look for patterns.
The system will find patterns
in some of your high-risk loan candidates,
or it will look for patterns
in some of your most successful employees.
Then it will match those patterns to the new applications.