- Virtual agents combined several different
artificial intelligence concepts.
Your agent needs to understand language
then the system needs to respond
in a way that seems natural.
It's really difficult to build your own system
that interacts with people in a natural way.
One system might be terrific at understanding language,
another might be pretty good at generating texts.
But it's a real challenge to have a system
that does both well at the same time.
That's why I'd be very difficult for you to build
your own virtual agent.
But on the upside, there are quite a few software companies
that sell their system as a service.
I have my computer here again,
and so let's see some of the top tools
for using virtual agents at your organization.
Virtual agents combine natural language processing,
natural language generation,
and automated decision making.
Let's look at one of the top virtual agents here.
If we go to Microsoft's website,
you can see that they have their own AI Chatbot.
Microsoft's Chatbot uses this gooey
to create a map of questions
and potential responses.
That means you don't have to use any coding
to create your own Chatbot.
It's really designed to be completely used as a service.
You can see here that you can buy the Chatbot
for a certain number of sessions.
Now, Microsoft also combines this Chatbot
with their dynamics 365 Customer Service.
So you can actually combine a virtual Chatbot
with customer service.
There's a flowchart style workflow that Microsoft
says it uses to create virtual agents quickly
and easily.
You can see that it connects up to a lot of other services
and the pricing is similar to just using the Chatbot.
There's also another service from a company
called Artificial Solutions.
They have a platform called Teneo.
This platform uses a series of algorithms
to do something that they call natural language interaction.
Much like Microsoft service,
it doesn't really require a lot of software development
in a similar graphics tools that allow you
to build your own conversations.
There's another company called DigitalWorkforce.ai,
and they have a slightly different take than Microsoft
or Artificial Solutions.
Instead of focusing on building out Chatbots,
this company wants you to hire their digital assistant.
They have a nice little demonstration on their website
of their top digital employee which they call Amelia.
This demonstration assumes that you're an employee
named John Smith,
so he can ask a simple question
like I need to reset my password.
Then Amelia will ask for some more information.
In this case, your employee ID.
We'll just put in an employee ID for John Smith here,
and then she'll ask for a verification.
She'll pretty much act just like a human chat person,
except this will all be automated
and in real time.
Because she has access to the backend data,
she can also do some real time automated decision-making.
Here she resets your password.
When you're done, you can just hit the reset button there
and then Amelia will go right back
to asking you other questions.
So this is kind of a nice little demonstration here
of how you can hire a virtual Chatbot
to do some simple administrative tasks.