- Remember that automated decision making systems work best
when they have access to massive amounts of data.
That's how they make the best analytical decisions.
These systems rely on other technologies
to gather up that data.
Now these automated decision systems can use data
from many different sources.
This might include past data
but it can also include current data
or data that's created in real time.
That's why you're seeing some organizations use IoT devices
to gather up data for these decision making systems.
IoT stands for Internet of things.
It usually refers small devices
that are connected to the internet.
The whole point of these devices
is to create real time data.
State electric companies are one
of the organizations doing interesting work
using IoT devices.
They connect these devices
to their automated decision making systems.
These companies put small communication devices
into your electric meter.
That way they can process your electricity use
in real time.
They record this data and try
to predict when you need more power.
They can gather this data for groups of houses,
cities, and even states.
They can then use it for statistical analysis
on statewide energy usage.
These companies use this data
in automated decision making systems
to try and create next generation smart grids.
An AI system can see very complex patterns on energy usage.
So these AI systems can route more power
to different parts of the grid in real time.
That way they make sure customers get the power they need.
But the AI system could also make decisions as well.
It could determine if customers are too wasteful.
Then the system might raise the rate
for that individual to encourage them
to increase their energy efficiency.
Newer IoT meters can even identify individual appliances
in someone's house.
At some point,
they might even be able to shut off outlets
if they detect an appliance is shorting out.
This stream of real time data combined
with AI decision making could create a system
that sees large scale patterns
while also keeping track of each outlet.
So if you're thinking about using this tool,
you might want to think carefully about what real time data
would be the most useful in your decision making.
Remember that AI systems do best
with massive amounts of data.
They're great at making analytical decisions
that don't require a lot of creativity.
The more data you collect,
the more powerful your system becomes.
If you decide to use IoT devices,
be sure to look for ways
to connect data sources to past trends.
It's not enough to see the data in real time.
Your AI decision making system needs
to compare this real time data to historical trends.
As always,
the quality of your data will let your system make
much more significant automated decisions.