- We've talked about how we can use
natural language generation or NLG
to create short paragraphs from different data sources.
This works well for organizations
that want to use text to explain data.
And if you think about it,
there are many scenarios
where you might want to explain data.
One place where this is increasingly common
is with online customer support systems.
In fact, a lot of support centers
involve a customer service representative
doing a little bit of research,
and then sending back text.
If you have a lot of data sources,
then it's not too difficult to imagine an NLG system
doing this heavy lifting.
Imagine that you just bought
a brand new flat screen television.
Then you go to the company's website
to figure out how to connect it
to some online streaming services.
Maybe you type a simple message
like how do I connect my television to Netflix?
An AI system can break that down into keywords.
So for this, they might search their database
for television and Netflix.
The application could send back a message
that says something like, "Thank you for your message,
"we have a few television sets
"that allow you to watch Netflix.
"Do you have our latest model, the HDI?"
Even in a simple exchange,
you have the AI system searching through a product catalog
to verify that certain television sets support Netflix.
It even lists out the latest model.
When your customer responds,
the AI system will have even more information.
It'll look through forums
and may even perform a search on websites.
With each message,
the AI system has a new set of keywords
to perform a more sophisticated search.
The more data this NLG system has access to,
the more useful the response.
You might get a message back that the television
has a brand new firmware update.
Then you'll get a response
to see if you need help installing the update.
NLG also gives organizations an opportunity
to reach out to customers to prevent problems.
Remember that the NLG system
sees communication as a data challenge.
So now the organization has a little bit more data
about how you use your television set.
It knows what type of television you have
and the fact that you like to use it to watch Netflix.
It now has all the data it needs
to send out messages to prevent future service issues.
Maybe Netflix changed their clients
so it no longer works with your television.
The organization could use their NLG system
to send you an email.
It might say that if you still use your television set
to watch Netflix,
then you might need to upgrade your firmware.
So with the help of your TV set,
you become just another data source for the NLG system.
It can use this data
to send you relevant customer service messages.