- [Instructor] Let's start looking at some tools
for Natural Language Generation or NLG.
We'll start out with an open source tool called SimpleNLG.
You could find it on GitHub.
Here, SimpleNLG.
You can see it's actively maintained.
This project was started by a university professor
named Ehud Reiter from the university
of Aberdeen in Scotland.
He later founded a company called Arria
which we'll see in a few minutes.
SimpleNLG is a realization engine
for Natural Language Generation.
It tries to produce natural sounding text.
To get started, you can just click on this tutorial here.
You can just click on Getting Started.
SimpleNLG is a Java library.
You can just download the zip file
and import it and can start using as Java class immediately.
Professor Reiter's blog is a pretty good source
of information on NLG.
It has a pretty imposing picture of him
and some great links to NLG resources.
He's also coauthored a book on NLG
called Building Natural Language Generation Systems.
This would be a great guide if you're a researcher
or a software developer looking to get
into natural language generation.
He also helped start a company called Arria,
which is one of the top commercial NLG platforms.
They have a product called NLG Studio,
so you can scroll down here.
Their focus is taking structured data that you might get
from a corporate database and then combining it
with natural language.
So that means you could take a nice chart
from Microsoft SQL Server
and then create natural language to describe the data.
There's a competing platform from Automated Insights,
which does something very similar.
They have a product called Wordsmith.
I'm just going to close this out here.
Wordsmith is really about creating stories
that sound like they were generated from a human author.
You can see here that the Automated Press uses Wordsmith.
Remember earlier, we had an example about using NLG
for updating corporate earnings reports.
That's one area where you can really use this product.
Like Arria, you can use this tool to add explanations
to structured data.
There's another company called Narrative Science.
This company is in Chicago and they started out using NLG
to create stories that summarize sporting events.
Since then they moved away from sports journalism
and more into corporate reporting.
Their main product is called Quill.
Much like the other NLG services,
it also focuses mostly on corporate dashboards
and reporting on structured data.
It uses NLG to explain complex data visualizations
to managers and executives.
So there are some of the great tools that you can use
when using NLG at your organization.
Each of these platforms has its own area
in which they excel.
Quill focuses more on readability
while the other two products try to focus more
on interpreting the data.
That means that one of these platforms
may work better than the other
based on your organization's needs.