- Automated decision making systems can do a lot of things
better than human customer service agents.
They can simply look at more data sources
and make more decisions in a shorter period of time.
But if you're thinking about using these tools,
you should actually think about it as supplementing agents
instead of replacing them.
In your organization there are generally two types
of decisions that you need to make.
There are analytical decisions and intuitive decisions.
Analytical decisions follow predictable patterns.
They usually involve a lot of data and statistical analysis.
So with a canceled flight, an AI system can use data
about the airport, the flight schedule,
and even the weather service.
Then it makes an analytical decision
about how to rebook your flight.
But sometimes businesses are forced to make decisions
about things that have never happened.
So if you think about March 2020,
many of the airlines were forced to shut down,
not because of weather, but because of a global pandemic.
Airlines had never had to shut down before
because of a pandemic, so there was no preexisting data.
As a result, many of the AI systems didn't work well
in the crisis.
Instead, many of the problems had to be fixed
by human customer service agents.
This was a much slower and much more complicated,
intuitive decision making process.
That's because each of these agents
had used their own human intuition to solve problems.
So you should think of it this way,
AI systems do extremely well when there's little uncertainty
and the system can rely on historical data.
Human customer service agents do well
when the problem is something that hasn't happened before.
Then the agent has to think intuitively about a solution.
So if you're thinking about using
AI automated decision making systems,
you should balance the two ways that your organization
has to make decisions.
If there's a lot of unpredictability,
then you'd be better served by giving human decision makers,
the tools that they need.
They can use these tools to address challenges
much more quickly.
On the other hand, a more analytical
AI automated decision making system
will do well if you have a lot of historical data.
Then you can focus on a system that reacts quickly.
So a parcel delivery service like UPS or FedEx
could really benefit from an automated
decision making system.
They have massive amounts of data on delivery times
and perhaps even alternative routes.
But if your business is in retail or hospitality,
then you might be better off
having some more intuitive human customer service agents.