- In the 1939 World's Fair,
one of the most popular attractions
was a 250-pound robot named Elektro.
He dazzled audiences while smoking,
blowing up balloons, and even telling jokes.
Many people believed they were just a few years away
from having their own Elektro
so it would vacuum their floors or drive them to work.
But as impressive as Elektro was, he had a serious flaw.
He was automated, but not intelligent.
So when you pressed a button, he could blow up a balloon,
but he didn't have the ability to learn and grow.
If you fast forward to today, you still see this confusion
around artificial intelligence and automation.
And some of this is intentional.
Many software and hardware vendors eagerly
and often incorrectly label their products
as artificial intelligence.
If you want to use this technology,
then it's important to understand the difference
between automation and artificial intelligence.
One of the very best books on artificial intelligence is
"Artificial Intelligence: A Modern Approach"
by Stuart Russell and Peter Norvig.
In this textbook,
the authors talk about how AI extends the reach
of the designer into unknown environments.
In a sense, the system will improve without any help
from the original designer.
So a defining component of AI is
that it will learn and grow.
That means if you're thinking about using this technology,
you should push back on any software vendor
that labels simple automation as artificial intelligence.
In fact, as a customer, you probably see this all the time.
Your tax software might advertise
that they use artificial intelligence to check your returns,
but the system isn't really coming up with a new way
for you to save on your taxes.
It's simply following very routine automation
on well-established tax code.
There's also a growing area
of robotic process automation, or RPA.
This is when software observes
how a human interacts with their computer.
Then it tries to repeat the same sequence.
These systems are sometimes called artificial intelligence,
but they're really just standard automation.
The software bots do exactly what they were shown,
almost like an old style tape recorder.
They never learn or adapt.
Another area you might see this is
with AI enhanced hardware.
AI systems usually require a lot
of floating point arithmetic.
This is a very resource-intensive type of computing.
That's why a lot of these earlier systems
used graphics processing units, or GPUs,
for better performance.
In fact, a lot of the AI enhanced hardware comes
from companies that manufactured graphics cards.
It turns out that the graphics card
that helps you play video games is also very good
at AI processing.
But like robotics processing automation,
this technology is not in itself intelligent.
So if you're using this technology,
you should really think of it in two ways.
Are the products you're buying actually using some form
of artificial intelligence,
or is this an impressive set of automations?
Second, you should think about the ways
you want to label your own products.
The marketing team might be enthusiastic
about the label of AI, but you should consider
whether you're actually creating products
that can learn and grow.
If these products can improve themselves over time,
then they really are enhanced with artificial intelligence.