- Imagine that you're flying to a friend's graduation party.
You're a loyal customer, so you fly the same airline.
When you arrive at the airport, you start to worry.
You see people gathering in front of monitors.
It turns out that your flight has been canceled
due to bad weather.
Almost immediately, you get a text on your phone.
It turns out that you've been booked on the next flight.
You also get a smart code with a coupon for a restaurant.
Now, all of this is happening instantaneously.
It had very little human intervention,
and it's all because your airline
uses something called automated decision-making.
Remember that AI systems do well when they have access
to tremendous amounts of data.
Using that data, the airline can build a system
that makes instant decisions.
It can do this in a fraction of the time
that it would take a human customer service agent.
The automated decision-making system
probably evaluated your customer loyalty.
That way it could figure out who to book first
on the next flight.
Then it did some probability analysis
to determine the likelihood
your new flight was departing on time.
For that, it might use data sources
from the National Weather Service.
It might even look at historical trends
of similar flights from the same airport.
Finally, it created coupons based on the probability
that you'd get something to eat before your next flight.
It might get this data from your airline credit card.
This AI system uses a combination of statistical techniques.
One of the most important is real-time data gathering.
The system uses real-time data about the weather,
the airport, and the flight status of arriving airplanes.
It also takes into account whether this is your home city,
or if you're connecting to a different flight.
The system might also use trend analysis.
It considers questions like how long does it take
for the airport to clear out?
How many people go to the restaurants?
How often do you travel?
And how will this impact your future buying decisions?
This system uses both data and trend analysis
to forecast different outcomes.
What's the likelihood that you'll arrive
close to your original arrival time?
What's the likelihood that your flight will take off
without any further delay?
Remember that the AI system sees this as a data challenge.
Then it looks for patterns
so it can better predict future outcomes.
In many ways, that makes the system uniquely qualified
to make real-time decisions.
A human customer service agent might be friendlier,
but it would be nearly impossible for them
to weigh all these different statistical outcomes.
So it would be harder for them to come up with a solution
that has the highest probability of success.
AI systems can also do automated decision-making
to help solve all kinds of business logistics challenges.
It's not just airlines that benefit
from this type of real-time decision making.