- Natural language processing is a very popular concept
in artificial intelligence.
That's why there are so many tools available.
Some of these tools are just commercial products
that you can buy from a software vendor,
but there are also open-source tools
that allow you to build your own system.
In the next two videos,
you'll see some of the most popular tools for NLP.
First, we'll talk about some of the toolkits
that you can use for natural language understanding.
Then you'll also see a very interesting paper
that evaluates which NLU system was the best
at understanding language.
In the next video, we'll look at some commercial
and open-source tools for natural language generation.
I have my trusty computer ready here,
so let's start looking at some of these AI tools.
When you're starting out with natural language processing,
a good place to start is using something called
the Natural Language Toolkit.
Let's just scroll down here and go to the website
for the Natural Language Toolkit.
This toolkit is written in Python.
It's freely available and simple to install.
You just have to know a little bit about Python.
All you have to do is import the NLTK Python library
and the data.
If you scroll back up here to the top,
there's a link to the FAQ.
It will give you some information about the license.
The NLTK uses an open-source Apache license.
That means that you could use it freely to learn,
and you could also use it in your products.
It uses both versions of Python,
but you'll probably want to use Python 3.4 going forward.
If you end up using NLTK,
you might want to get a copy of their book.
It has a lot of information about NLTK,
plus gives you some code samples that they call recipes.
So if we go back here,
you can see some instructions on how to install.
It's a little bit easier to install on Mac and Linux
than it is on Windows.
In Windows, you just have to install this binary for Python.
You also need to install the data
to make sure that the library works correctly.
So that's pretty easy here.
There's also some instructions for installing the data.
So Natural Language Toolkit is a great tool to start
learning about natural language processing or NLP.
There's another great resource available
for natural language understanding, or NLU.
If you go to Google Scholar,
you can see there's a paper that's freely available
called "A Comparison and Critique of
Natural Language Understanding Tools".
This paper will give you an overview
of various natural language understanding tools.
I downloaded the paper here.
Just double click it to open.
This is written by two professors in Italy.
What they did was that they went through and did a survey
of many of the top natural language understanding platforms.
They wanted to see which platform understood
the intent of the language.
They wanted to see which one worked best.
They tested Google's Dialogueflow, Facebook's Wit.ai,
Microsoft's LUIS, IBM's Watson Conversation,
Amazon Lex, and Recast.ai.
Each of these tools are about understanding language,
and you can see that they went through
each one at a time here and evaluated them
to see how well they understood language.
So if you scroll down to the very end here,
you can see their conclusion,
where they talk about which one of these tools
performs the best at understanding the intent of language.
You can see that for this study,
they found that Watson was the platform
that understood the intent of language best.
This paper came out in 2018,
so the results might be different today.
But if you're thinking about using
natural language understanding,
this paper shows a great way
to evaluate these different tools.
You can use some of their suggestions
to test these different platforms for your own organization.