- So we've seen that you can use supervised machine learning
to make better decisions
in your AI automated decision making systems.
With supervised machine learning,
you can also make really accurate predictions
at a pretty low cost.
You no longer need a manual process
to go through job candidates or loan applications.
If you want to use these systems in your organization,
then you need to make sure that you have access
to a lot of data.
You'd want to train your machine learning algorithms
with data about your low-risk loan customers
or your best employees.
Then the system can match new candidates
to your existing data.
Now if you think about it,
you're putting a lot of trust into these algorithms.
And for all these systems might find patterns
that humans can't really comprehend.
What really makes a person your best employee?
What are the factors that make a student successful?
What kind of person always pays back their loans?
The system doesn't look at the personal qualities
of these people, it just looks at the data.
That means it might find that wealthy applicants
are more likely to pay back a home.
It also might find that students
who come from expensive neighborhoods
are more likely to succeed in school.
Because it's just working off the data,
the system will happily deny a loan
to anyone below a certain income level.
It will also confidently refuse to admit students
if they come from less expensive neighborhoods.
So if there's any inequality in the system,
your machine learning algorithms
will not only pick up on that inequality,
but also use that criteria to make future decisions.
That means that this inequality might get amplified.
Think of it this way.
Imagine you work for a software development company.
Your executive decides that they want to use
a machine learning automated decision making system
to rate employment applications.
So you gather up the employment applications
for your top 500 employees.
Then you use this data to train
your machine learning algorithm
to find employees who closely match these top applications.
Now say that out of the 500 top employees,
only 150 of them are women.
When you train your system to rate new employees,
it's learned from your own data
that women are less likely to do well on your organization.
That means it will give female candidates
a lower rating when they submit their application.
So when you're building out
these automated decision making systems,
you have to be careful about how much bias
you feed into the system.
If the data you provide is biased,
then the system is only going to become more biased
as it looks through new data.
This kind of ethical challenge has been a big issue
in machine learning automated decision making systems.
In fact regulators in the European Union
have talked about creating a right of explanation.
If it's enacted,
this will give people the right to look at the criteria
that the system uses when making decisions about them.