- I hope you've enjoyed this course
on artificial intelligence.
Throughout the course,
we covered some very high level AI concepts.
You've seen how machine learning
and artificial neural networks can help you see patterns
in massive datasets.
You've also seen how biometrics and natural language
can be broken down into regular data.
Once these AI systems can use this data,
it becomes just another form of pattern matching.
So that means you can create AI systems
that can read and write texts,
predict your behavior,
or identify you in a crowd.
Now that you've taken this course,
there's actually a few different ways
you can continue to learn about AI.
You can start to drill down into specific tools
so you can learn more about something
like natural language processing with Python.
But you could also choose to take a deeper dive
into any of the AI concepts.
There are plenty of courses on machine learning,
deep learning,
and artificial neural networks.
These AI tools continue to improve and evolve,
so please feel free to follow me on LinkedIn.
Here, I'll post about interesting new things
in the world of AI.
Thank you for watching this course.
I hope you continue learning about
this fascinating technology.
Then you can find creative ways
to explore and use artificial intelligence.