- In 2016, the famous computer scientist,
Geoffrey Hinton said,
"It's quite obvious
that we should stop training radiologists."
He believed that machine learning systems
could make better decisions when looking at x-rays.
He thought that these systems would quickly overtake humans,
so there was no need to train radiologists.
Now, we've seen that these systems can run in a few ways.
Through supervised machine learning
or unsupervised machine learning.
For supervised machine learning,
you teach the system to see the pattern.
So you might have radiologists
gather thousands of x-rays
where a patient needed back surgery.
This would be your training set.
Then you'd feed it into the machine learning algorithm.
Once the system was well trained,
then you can have it look through new x-rays.
So it would try to match the patterns.
Then it would make a decision
about whether this patient needs back surgery.
This kind of automated decision-making system
would make split-second decisions
based on the machine learning algorithm's
advanced pattern matching.
The advantages of this type of system
is it can make instantaneous decisions.
It might even be included as part of the x-ray machine.
Also, if you believe professor Hinton,
it might be much more accurate.
The machine could see tiny abnormalities
that it would be difficult or impossible
for a human radiologist to identify.
You could also use unsupervised machine learning.
Here you would let the machine decide
how to cluster together different x-rays.
Then a technician could look at these clusters
and try to identify any abnormalities.
If you use this approach,
the machine learning algorithm
might find diseases or disorders
that haven't even been discovered.
But most of the work in this area
has been using supervised machine learning.
AI researchers have a list of disorders,
and then they create training sets
collected by human radiologists.
The system then uses automated decision-making
to come up with a recommendation.
So what do you think of professor Hinton's idea?
Would you prefer to have your x-ray viewed by a radiologist
or by a machine learning algorithm?
If you think about it,
there's a downside to replacing human radiologists
with an automated decision-making system.
Supervised machine learning systems
require human experts to create the initial training set.
If you stop training radiologists,
then there won't be that level of human expertise
to help train the system.
This might be fine if there are no new diseases
or disorders,
but what if the machine finds a new abnormality?
Remember that supervised machine learning systems
have trouble when they see something completely new.
You could also use unsupervised machine learning,
but then there's the risk
that if the system clusters together
different abnormalities,
there won't be an experienced radiologist
to identify the disease.
So you can see that there are a lot of different ways
to use machine learning for automated decision making.
The key is figuring out
how much control you want to leave in the hands of the system.