- The real power of artificial neural networks
is their ability to supercharge machine learning.
In fact,
there's actually a relationship between the size
of the network and how well the system sees patterns.
Remember that artificial neural networks
have layers of neurons.
There's the input layer, the output layer,
and then the layers in between.
These layers in between
are typically called the hidden layers.
Some systems have many hidden layers
and this is usually called
a deep learning artificial neural network.
That's because the network is many layers deep.
Companies like Google have really embraced
deep learning artificial neural networks.
They use them to look for complex patterns.
You may have heard that Google
used their deep learning network
to teach a machine learning system how to play video games.
The system observed many hours of gameplay
and then looked for patterns on how to win the game.
Later, they used that same technology
to teach the system how to play
an ancient Chinese game called Go.
Go is thought to be so complex
that there is many variations in games
as there are atoms in the universe.
So clearly that's a lot of data.
At first,
the deep learning network observed thousands
of experts playing the game.
Then after awhile,
they programmed the system to play against itself.
It was able to discover many of the different patterns
that led to winning the game.
So you might be wondering why a company
like Google would spend so much time figuring out
how to play an ancient game.
The reason is that Google is using the same technology
to better understand their users' behavior.
So think of it this way.
If Google can use this system to master such a complex game,
then it's actually pretty easy to predict
whether you're going to buy a new car.
It uses the same underlying technology.
Earlier, we talked about how machine learning
can help you make better predictions.
If Google can predict with 95% certainty
that you'll buy a product,
then that has an incredible commercial value.
So if you're thinking about applying this technology
in your organization,
you have to consider a few things.
It's actually not difficult
to create an artificial neural network.
There's even a few free tools
that you'll see later in the course.
But what is difficult is getting the type
of data you'll need to fine tune your deep learning.
Now Google easily has access to petabytes of user data
but what type of data does your organization have?
What type of behavior would you like to predict?
Some of the best places to look are the parts
of your organization that run on gut level instinct.
If you have the right data,
then you might find that some of these systems
actually do a better job predicting than even some
of your most experienced employees.