- So we know that Machine Learning is like a giant label gun
that classifies tremendous amounts of data.
But to classify machine learning algorithms
still rely on humans to identify
what it is they're labeling.
This is typically called training
your machine learning algorithms.
So let's imagine you start a business
where you sort through tons of trash
to separate out the recyclable material.
From a machine learning perspective,
this is a very complicated data challenge.
There might be thousands of pieces of garbage
going down the conveyor belt
and the machine learning algorithm
needs to identify each piece.
From a data perspective,
this is a pretty standard classification problem.
A human operator trains the system on what's recyclable.
So in this case, you'll make piles of aluminum, plastic,
cardboard, and paper.
Then you'd make piles of food waste
or plastic bags.
These different piles would be called the data training set
and the machine learning algorithm
would look for patterns in the recyclable materials.
That way could correctly label future trash
as it's coming down the belt.
In a sense it's learning what's recyclable.
Now, remember you need a human operator
to create those first piles of recyclable material.
So this is typically called supervised machine learning
and operators supervises the machine
and tells the algorithms
when they're misidentifying something as recyclable.
For now, this is the most popular way
that machine learning algorithms classify data.
But there's another way for these machine learning
algorithms to work with data,
it's called unsupervised machine learning.
Unsupervised machine learning doesn't classify data,
instead it works to create clusters of data.
So imagine that a human operator doesn't create
those first training sets,
it just asks the machine to identify patterns in the data.
That means that the unsupervised machine learning algorithm
would look at all the trash coming down the conveyor belt.
It wouldn't get those first piles
sorted by recyclables in waste.
Then it would cluster the trash into different groups
that make sense to the algorithm.
There's no training set,
so the system creates its own groups.
It might make piles of garbage that are all the same color,
or it might create piles of garbage
based on the size of the material.
It might even create piles of trash
based on some qualities that humans can't perceive.
As you can imagine, unsupervised learning
wouldn't be very useful for this recycling plant,
but it might be useful for something
like a pharmaceutical company
or an automated stock trading system.
You might want to find patterns that humans
haven't yet identified.
It might even lead to discovery of a new drug.
So if you're thinking about using supervised
machine learning, start by identifying
what data you'd like to classify,
then try to gather up some massive data sets.