- Machine learning is one of the richest areas
in artificial intelligence.
That's because most companies are still struggling
on what to do with their data.
A lot of companies have gotten really good
at collecting massive amounts of data.
Now, the challenge is turning that data into something
that can help with accurate predictions and analysis.
The good news about machine learning is that
since it's been around for such a long time,
there are many different tools to choose from.
Companies and universities
have been developing tools for decades.
Most of them are easily available and free to use.
Now remember that machine learning is often the tool
you'll use to build many of your AI systems.
That means that you can use machine learning tools,
to build systems in natural language processing,
automated decision making, and even speech recognition.
I brought up my computer here again,
so let's start looking at some of these
great machine learning tools.
If you just started learning about machine learning,
one of the very best places to start
is with a project called Scikit-learn.
You can go to Scikit-learn here, you can see that
this is a machine learning implementation in Python.
It's built on a bunch of Python projects
and it's open source.
You can even use it in your projects
because it uses the very permissive BSD license.
The reason why this is such a good place to start,
is it's really powerful,
you can use a lot of machine learning algorithms
like classification and clustering.
There's even support for regression.
So this is a great project,
and you can actually use Scikit-learn
on top of cloud-based machine learning platforms
from Microsoft and IBM.
A lot of companies also use these
cloud-based machine learning services.
One of the big ones is Amazon.
And so this is machine learning service
that you can get on Amazon.
SageMaker is one of the big services
that they have on their machine learning platform.
As you can imagine, SageMaker connects up
with a lot of Amazon's other cloud-based services.
So that means you could upload your organizational data
to one of their cloud databases,
and then use SageMakers' machine learning algorithms
to analyze that data.
Another cloud-based machine learning service
is from Microsoft.
It's part of their Azure cloud services platform.
You can actually use their Scikit-learn framework,
on top of this Azure machine learning platform,
along with others.
You can also use something called
the Machine Learning Studio.
This tool allows you to upload data
and use drag and drop elements,
to analyze the data,
with their machine learning algorithms.
Another big cloud platform,
is IBM Watson Machine Learning.
And again, you can use a lot of the top frameworks
with this cloud platform.
You can use Scikit-learn and some other great platforms,
that you'll see later on.
This platform uses a concept they call pipelines.
You can pipeline in different data sources
and analyze the data using machine learning.
You can also stream data in from other sources.
Here's an example of how you can save a branch model,
from the statistics software package, SPSS,
using this Watson Machine Learning Platform.
There's a lot of variability
between these different services.
Amazon and Microsoft do classification and clustering,
while IBM focuses mostly on just classification.
Microsoft has a recommendation engine,
while the other two do not.
Amazon and IBM have built in machine learning algorithms,
but with Microsoft, you have to bring your own.
But most of them have the flexibility
to use frameworks like Scikit-learn.
And as you'll see later,
they all support the popular TensorFlow framework.