- Now let's take a look
at how you can connect machine learning
to some other tools and concepts.
Let's think about how this might work
with something like natural language processing.
Remember that machine learning
generally can be used in two different ways.
There's supervised machine learning,
where you provide the algorithm
with an initial training set.
And then unsupervised machine learning,
where the algorithm discovers its own patterns in the data.
So imagine you wanted to build
an NLP machine learning system.
This new system would process
all of the social media data on your organization.
Then it would summarize this data into a weekly report
so that executives know how people feel about your company.
If you are in charge of developing this application,
would you use supervised or unsupervised machine learning?
With supervised machine learning,
you could try to classify your data into different moods.
In this case, your team would label the moods,
and then find social media to put into the training set.
So maybe you would create a mood called satisfied
and then your team would find posts of satisfied customers.
You can then use this technique to generate
dozens or even hundreds of different labeled moods.
Once you have this training set,
you could train your machine learning system
to find millions of posts that follow the same pattern.
What do you think of the advantages and disadvantages
of this type of supervised machine learning system?
One thing you might notice
is that your team creates the initial moods.
So in a sense, you're creating the labels
and then trying to fit the data into these categories.
That means that the system could break down
if the data doesn't fit into one of these moods.
If a customer wasn't satisfied or dissatisfied,
then the system would have trouble knowing what to do.
On the other hand, you could have the system
cluster the data into different groups
that it identifies on its own.
So you could use unsupervised machine learning
and natural language processing
to cluster the data into groups.
So the result would be that the machine learning system
would create clusters of social media data.
If it worked well, then these clusters
generally would be saying the same thing.
Then you could look at each cluster and try to figure out
what the customer is trying to communicate.
Maybe it's sarcasm, disappointment,
or a completely new idea.
This might work well if your organization
is involved with something completely new or unexpected.
Maybe a famous celebrity used your product,
or maybe there's a defect in your product
that hasn't been identified by your engineers.
So in some ways, an unsupervised machine learning system
has a lot more flexibility.
At the same time, this flexibility has a cost.
You might get what's called a lot of noise in your data.
That means that the system will probably find groups
that are difficult to identify.
Some of them may even appear randomly clustered together.
So if you're thinking about using this technology,
try to balance the flexibility
of unsupervised machine learning
against the clear classifications you get
from supervised machine learning.