- A few years ago, I was working for an organization
that handled tremendous amounts of credit card data.
Their entire business centered
around analyzing customer purchases
and recommending promotions based on their interests.
So when a customer logged in to pay their bill,
they had the option of adding a digital coupon
to their credit card.
So it might be a coupon for a restaurant.
If a customer adds the coupon,
they'll automatically get a small discount
when they try out the restaurant.
So if you think about it,
this company is analyzing massive amounts of data.
Each customer might have hundreds
of transactions every month.
The major credit card companies
have tens of millions of customers.
So that's billions of transactions
and several petabytes of data.
This type of processing wouldn't be practical
with just one system.
So this business created an artificial neural network
to analyze all this data.
And remember, the data on its own
isn't necessarily valuable.
It's just a list of mundane transactions attached
to an anonymous customer ID.
What is valuable is the analysis that the company provides.
In this case,
the credit card companies wanted a way to accurately predict
where customers would use their credit cards.
It's easy to see where a customer has been.
The real challenge is
to predict new places the customer might go.
That means that the credit card company
could sell promotions to other businesses,
and businesses would be happy to pay for these promotions
because they could get new customers.
Now, remember, there's two main types of machine learning.
There's supervised machine learning
and unsupervised machine learning.
Supervised machine learning classifies data
based on labels that humans create.
So you come up with different classifications,
and then the machine sorts them into groups.
With unsupervised machine learning,
the AI system creates its own groups.
Here, it clusters data together
based on very sophisticated patterns.
This credit card processing company actually used
a combination of both unsupervised and supervised learning.
The first thing it did was allow the machine
to create clusters of different customers
who had very similar spending habits.
So as a customer, you would be grouped together
with people who spend money in similar ways.
Then it looked for crossover businesses.
So let's say you used your credit card
to go to Mexican food restaurants, buy wine,
and visit Arizona.
The machine would cluster you together with someone
who also buys wine and travels to Arizona.
Then it would send you promotions
for a local Mexican food restaurant.
Once the machine learning algorithm
clustered customers into these groups,
the artificial neural network would then classify them
with different customer labels.
So in this case, they created labels for customers
who are more flexible and open to new experiences.
Then the other label were customers
who tended not to like new foods or restaurants.
This artificial neural network
using machine learning algorithms was able
to find new businesses that these customers might like.
Then they classified these customers into people
who were more likely to try new food.
By doing this, they were able to micro-target
the very best customers for these promotions.