- Many of these artificial intelligence tools and concepts
are difficult to break down into distinct groups.
A lot of times what you see is a combination of AI tools
blended together to create a complex system.
You've seen AI automated decision-making systems.
These work well when the system needs to make
analytical decisions based on large data sets.
You've also learned a little bit
about natural language processing.
This is usually broken down into two separate processes.
There's natural language understanding, or NLU,
and natural language generation, or NLG.
There's also another closely related technology called
automated speech recognition or ASR.
A lot of organizations are starting to plan out
how to use these different tools to meet their needs.
So imagine you work for an organization that wants to build
an automated customer response system.
Let's say that you want your customers to be able
to open up an online chat, then make quick changes to items
that they've purchased from your website.
This chat system could use natural language processing.
It would translate what the customer asks
into something the system can understand.
Then you could use automated decision making
to make real changes to the order in real time.
That means your customers could make changes
just by chatting with your automated system.
There are many ways that businesses could benefit
from a combination of both automated decision making
and natural language processing.
This could be useful if your organization
works with logistics.
A package delivery company could reroute shipments based on
information they get from the customer.
You might reroute a package to where the customer works
or leave their package with a trusted neighbor.
Or for the airline industry, a customer could ask questions
about alternative flights and then get rerouted
using the same system.
If you work in manufacturing, you might be able
to set up a system that could answer questions.
This same system could even set up emergency deliveries
to some of your most loyal customers.
Your system could automate all these requests
long after your employees have gone home.
There's certainly online tools that your company
currently uses that might be able to accomplish
some of the same things.
But an automated decision-making system will also be able
to incorporate massive amounts of new data.
If your customer is trying to reroute their flight,
then they might not want to research
all your airline's available routes.
If they want to change their order,
then they might not be aware of everything
that's for sale in your product catalog.
An AI decision-making system will analyze all this data
and make decisions on your customer's behalf.
If you combine it with NLP, then the system can
communicate with your customer in a way that feels familiar.