- So we've seen how to use artificial intelligence
to generate natural sounding text.
Natural language generation, or NLG,
works best when the system has access
to many different data sources.
Generally NLG is about getting your AI system to write.
But as most grade school students will tell you,
writing is only half the equation.
AI systems also need to read.
This is typically called natural language understanding
or NLU.
Now it would be easier to talk about AI systems
as reading and writing
instead of understanding and generating.
But remember, even though the end result might be the same,
the AI system is doing something very different
from what you do when you read and write.
So think about a simple conversation you might have.
Imagine a new Indian food restaurant
opened up close to where you work.
One day, a coworker asks you a question,
did you and Susan try the new Indian food restaurant?
Then you answer back, actually it was a little too spicy.
Then they ask, will you go back?
Then you say, I don't know.
Now this conversation is pretty seamless
from a human perspective,
but if you look at it from the perspective of an AI system
you can start to see how this gets really complicated.
The first challenge is that you need to understand
a lot of context.
When your coworker asks you
if you tried the new restaurant,
they're really asking if you went there for the first time.
When you responded that it was too spicy,
you're answering their question
and then adding more information.
You're saying whether or not you liked the food.
So you wouldn't know if the food was spicy,
unless you went to the restaurant.
Finally, when your coworker asks
if you want to go back your answers a little irregular,
you say you don't know.
But in this case it doesn't mean
that you don't know what they're asking.
Instead, it means that you don't know
whether or not the food was good enough to go back.
Remember that the AI system
is only looking at data and patterns.
That means that the system must have a lot
of underlying data to make sense of this simple exchange.
The system will need to know
what trying a restaurant means in this context.
It will also have to know that the food being spicy
is actually an answer to a question.
Then it has to know that you not knowing
whether you'll go back is actually your judgment
about the quality of the restaurant.
It's not that you don't know what your coworker's asking.
If the AI system didn't understand your meaning
when you said, don't know,
it might have responded with something like,
would you like me to repeat the question?
Because it might incorrectly assume
that you didn't know what the person was asking.
In many ways, NLU is really the most challenging component
of natural language processing.
That's because it's very difficult
to have a conversation with an AI system
if they don't first understand what you're saying.