- Are you one of those people who remembers someone's face
better than you remember their name?
That's not that unusual.
In fact, from a young age, most humans are excellent
at tracking faces.
Of course, each person's face is a little bit different.
Eyes, nose, lips, and ears, all vary slightly
from person to person,
and these differences can be turned into data.
You can calculate the exact distance of all of your features
and come up with a series of numbers.
Generally, we call this biometric data.
These are the distinct, measurable characteristics
that are used to identify individuals.
This data can measure your fingerprints, your DNA,
or even the sound of your voice.
Then you can gather this data
and machine learning algorithms will look for patterns.
So imagine that you call up a customer service line,
but you're not really getting the help you need.
As your frustration grows your voice sounds more strange.
Your breathing could become irregular
and artificial intelligence agents
would then warn a supervisor
that there's an unhappy customer.
An artificial intelligence system looks at biometrics,
like it would any other type of data.
It would compare your voice with hundreds of thousands
of other conversations.
Than an engineer might use supervised machine learning
to train the system to identify angry customers.
You might not think of your face, your fingerprints
or your voice as data, but to a machine learning system
it's just numbers and probability.
Widespread facial recognition is one
of the more controversial ways of using biometrics.
Remember that machine learning systems operate best
when they're dealing with massive amounts of data.
So that means that these systems can easily look
at video footage and identify people on the screen.
Many cities are starting to use this technology
to find missing people or identify a person's location.
Of course, there's some serious data ethics issues
around whether or not government should be allowed
to track everyone in real time.
But whether or not you think this is appropriate,
it's certainly well within the capabilities
of AI machine learning systems.
In the 2020 pandemic many healthcare workers
were given biometric rings.
These rings could transmit their body temperature
and other data to machine learning systems.
These systems were able to process the data in real time,
so it was able to predict whether there was an outbreak
in the hospital, but only a few healthcare staff
wore the biometric rings.
Like all machine learning systems,
they require lots of data to make better decisions.
If millions of people were wearing the rings,
then it might've been a very valuable way
to track the spread of the virus.
If you're thinking about using this technology,
you should start thinking about biometric data
in the same way as your machine learning system.
Imagine it as complex data where the machine looks
for patterns.
Then you should think about what value these patterns have
to your organization.