- So now you've seen that machine learning algorithms
can act like giant label guns.
Classifying and clustering data together.
And these algorithms can be pretty powerful.
They can classify people as good loan candidates,
they can find students who might succeed at your university.
One challenge with these machine learning algorithms
is that they can be pretty processor intensive.
As you can imagine, it takes a very powerful system
to look through petabytes of data.
But this challenge isn't a new one.
And as far back as the early 1940s, computer scientists
were considering ways to expand the power
of computing systems.
What they came up with was something called
an Artificial Neural Network.
These networks are loosely inspired by the physiology
of the human brain.
A neuron is a nerve cell in your brain, that forms
a network to communicate and store information.
Your biological neurons communicate with each other
through something called synapses.
These are small gaps between the cells that send electrical
and chemical impulses.
An artificial neural network uses
something called artificial neurons or nodes.
These nodes connect to other nodes in the network
and pass information through electrical signals.
The network is typically arranged in layers.
The first layer is called the input layer.
And this layer is responsible for accepting the data.
The data then goes through other layers
of processing, before it goes out the output layer.
So think of it this way, imagine you had a room
with 20 people.
These people were arranged in four rows
of five people each.
Each person is holding a notepad.
Now imagine you have a deck of playing cards.
You start passing out a card to each person
in the front row.
If the card is red, they'd pass it to
the person right behind them.
If the card is black, then they'd pass it to the person next
to the person behind them.
Each row of people does the exact same thing.
Now using their notepads, people would also keep track
of every time they received a red or black card.
If they received more red cards, then they would start
to learn that red was the more common color.
Then the people behind them would also share their notes.
Over time, this group of people would be able
to process cards into red and black very quickly.
They'd also be able to accurately predict
whether their card was more likely to be red or black.
The point of creating a system like this
is that it becomes very good at classifying
and clustering massive amounts of data.
And you're able to distribute the processing power
to a network of individual nodes.
So instead of having one computer trying
to do everything, you can have a network
of nodes using very simple algorithms.
These artificial neural networks can really expand
the capabilities of machine learning.
They allow artificial intelligence systems
to find extremely complex patterns
while sifting through, massive amounts of data.